原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     小酸奶
翻译     丁小七  章鱼X
翻译     南鹞北鹰  嘟嘟矢  莱吉
校对     cazorp  somehacker
时间轴   Ans
后期     8T
总监     somehacker
密苏里州 地球 1980年
银河护卫队2
跟我来 慢点
Come on! - Slow down.
你在说什么 小百合 快点
What do you say, my River Lily? Come on!
- 你要带我去哪 - 来 来 来
- Where are you taking me? - Come on, come on, come on.
- 瞧 - 哦 真漂亮
- Look. Look. - Oh, it's beautiful!
我本以为它适应不了这片土地
I was afraid it wouldn't take to this soil.
没想到长得这么快
But it rooted quickly.
很快它就会到处都是
And soon it'll be everywhere.
遍布全宇宙
All across the universe.
我听不懂你在说什么
Well I don't know what you're talking about...
但你说话的样子真可爱
but I like the way you say it.
我的心属于你
My heart is yours...
梅乐迪丝 奎尔
Meredith Quill.
真不敢相信自己爱上了一个外星人
I can't believe I fell in love with a spaceman.
34年后
34 YEARS LATER
君王星
THE SOVEREIGN PLANET
表演时间到 同志们
Showtime, a- holes!
它随时会出现
It's gonna be here any minute.
这里就是它的葬身之地
Which will be its loss.
我以为你要用剑的
I thought your thing was a sword.
我们是被雇来阻止一只可以多维度穿梭的怪物汲取这能源电池的
We've been hired to stop an inter- dimensional beast...
你觉得我会用剑来搞定吗
from feeding on those batteries, and I'm gonna stop it with a sword?
不是一般都是你用剑我用枪吗
It's just, swords were your thing and guns were mine
看来我们今天都要用枪了
but I guess we're both doing guns now. I just didn't know that.
德拉克斯 你怎么没有穿咱们的太空队服
Drax, why aren't you wearing one of Rocket's aero- rigs?
- 硌着疼 - 疼
- It hurts. - Hurts?
我的乳头有些敏感
I have sensitive nipples.
哈哈哈 我的乳头疼 笑死我啦
Ha ha ha! My nipples hurt! Oh goodness me!
他呢 他又在那搞什么玩意儿
What about him? What's he doing?
我正在整咱的音响呢 这样可以边听歌边工作
I'm finishing this so we can listen to tunes while we work.
- 这时候整这玩意儿 - 怪奎尔啊
- How is that a priority? - Blame Quill.
就他才这么喜欢听音乐
He's the one who loves music so much.
不 这点我同意德拉克斯 现在确实没必要弄这个
No, I actually agree with Drax on this. That's hardly important right now.
哦 好吧 听你的 奎尔
Oh, Okay. Sure, Quill.
我是认真的 这次我站德拉克斯
No, seriously, I side with Drax.
我知道 我知道你非常认真
No, I understand that. You're being very serious right now.
我得看到你眨眼睛
I can clearly see you winking.
糟糕 我用左眼了
Dammit. I'm using my left eye?
我是格鲁特
I am Groot!
他们根本没在看你
They were not looking at you funny.
情况不妙
That's intense.
银河护卫队2
克里斯·普拉特
佐伊·索尔达娜
戴夫·巴蒂斯塔
范·迪塞尔 格鲁特宝宝
布莱德利·库珀 火箭浣熊
迈克尔·鲁克
凯伦·吉兰
格鲁特
Groot!
庞·克莱门捷夫
伊丽莎白·德比茨基
克里斯·沙利文
格鲁特躲开点 你会受伤的
Groot, get out of the way! You're going to get hurt.
嗨
Hi.
肖恩·古恩
汤米·弗拉纳根
劳拉·哈德克
史泰龙
库尔特·拉塞尔
ORANGE字幕组原创翻译
翻译 小龙 Joyce cc西
陶泥 Rebecca iM 阿微
校对 派派嫁我
协调&后期 Libsu苏苏
压制 小明
不 吐出来 乖 快吐出来
No, no! Spit it out, spit it out, c'mon.
真恶心
Disgusting!
这怪物的皮太厚了 外边根本穿不透
The beast's hide is too thick to be pierced from the outside.
我要从里边把它切开
I must cut through it from the inside.
不 不要 德拉克斯 等等
No, no, Drax! Wait a minute!
他在搞什么鬼
What is he doing?
他说皮太厚没法从外部刺穿 所以他
He said the skin is too thick to be pierced from the outside, so he...
- 神经病啊 - 我刚要拦住他
- That doesn't make any sense! - I tried telling him that!
它的皮无论内外都是一样厚的
Skin's the same level of thickness from the inside as from the outside!
我知道
I realize that.
它的喉咙有一处伤口
There is a cut on its neck.
火箭 让它往上边看
Rocket, get it to look up.
嗨 海猴子 我在这
Hey, giant sea monkey! I'm here!
小心 奎尔
Watch it, Quill!
耶 我单枪匹马
Yes! I have single handedly
灭了这只怪物
vanquished the beast!
干嘛
What?
- 这玩意儿叫什么来着 - 安纽拉斯电池
- What are they called again? - Anulax batteries.
傻不啦叽电池
Harbulary batteries.
这跟我刚说的简直天差地别
That's nothing like what I just said.
这些东西价值不菲
But they're worth thousands of units a piece, which is...
这也是为什么君王星雇我们来保护它们
why the Sovereign hired us to protect them.
注意自己的言辞 他们可不好打交道
Careful what you say around these folks, they're easily offended.
动不动就判死刑
The cost of transgression is death.
感谢你们为此铤而走险
We thank you Guardians for putting your lives on the line.
我们不能让自己的人民去冒险
We could not risk the lives of our own Sovereign citizens.
每一个公民都是精心设计的
Every citizen is born exactly as designed by the community.
无论生理还是精神上都毫无瑕疵
Impeccable, both physically and mentally.
我们掌控着后代的基因
We control the DNA of our progeny
在生命舱中培育着他们
germinating them in birthing pods.
我还是更倾向于用传统的方式造人
I guess I prefer to make people the old fashioned way.
或许哪天你可以给我上堂历史课
Well. Perhaps someday you could give me a history lesson...
用我们祖先最传统古老的方式
in the archaic ways of our ancestors.
纯粹作学术讨论
For academic purposes.
我很荣幸 从学术的角度来说
I would be honored. Yes. In the name of research...
这或许会
I think that could be...
相当 呃 令人难以接受
pretty uh, repulsive. I'm...
- 我不是那么随便的男人 - 不好意思
- I'm not into that kind of casual... - Please...
贵国还承诺了一些报酬
Your people promised something in exchange for our services.
兑现之后我们会马上离开
Bring it and we shall gladly be on our way.
家庭团聚 赞
Family reunion. Yay!
我知道她是你的妹妹
I understand she is your sister.
她不过是我要去赞达尔星球领的一笔赏金罢了
She's worth no more to me than the bounty due for her on Xandar.
我们的士兵逮捕她时 她正在企图偷电池
Our soldiers apprehended her attempting to steal the batteries.
任君处置
Do with her as you please.
感谢您 阿耶莎主教大人
We thank you, High Priestess Ayesha.
您来自何方 奎尔先生
What is your heritage, Mr. Quill?
- 我母亲来自地球 - 那您父亲呢
- My mother was from Earth. - And your father?
反正不是密苏里州的 我就知道这么多
He ain't from Missouri. That's all I know.
在你身上
I see it within you.
我看到了非正统血脉
An unorthodox genealogy.
一个相当鲁莽的决定
A hybrid that seems particularly...
所诞生的混血儿
reckless
人们都说你们星球的人都是狂妄自大的混蛋
You know, they told me you people were conceited douchebags.
但这应该是假话 对吧
But that isn't true at all..
啊 糟糕 我又眨错眼睛了是吗
Ah, shit. I'm using my wrong eye again, aren't I?
不好意思 本来打算背着你们眨的
I'm sorry, that was... that was meant to be behind your back.
他们没杀你 算你走运
Count yourself blessed they didn't kill you.
你是在说 他们想买些电池吗
You're telling me. You want to buy some batteries??
好的 我们去赞达尔领奖金吧
All right, let's get baldly to Xandar and collect that bounty.
Lake Shore Drive (by Aiotta Haynes Jeremiah)
There's a road I'd like to tell you about, lives in my home town
Lake Shore Drive the road is called and it'll take you up or down
From rats on up to riches fifteen minutes you can fly
Pretty blue lights along the way, help you right on by
And the blue lights shining with a heavenly grace, help you right on by
And there ain't no road just like it
Anywhere I found
Running south on Lake Shore Drive heading into town
Just slippin' on by on LSD, Friday night trouble bound
关于我爸的事
old staff of my father
她以为她是谁啊
Who does she think she is?
我知道你对这个有心结
I know you're sensitive about that.
并不是什么心结 只是不晓得他是谁罢了
I'm not sensitive about it. I just don't know who he is.
抱歉 如果刚才显得像我在跟大祭司调情的话
Sorry if it seemed like I was flirting with the High Priestess.
- 我并没有那个意思 - 你有我也不在乎
- I wasn't. - I don't care if you were.
我觉得你挺在乎的
Well I feel like you do care.
这才是为什么我要道歉 真对不起
That's why I'm apologizing. So, sorry.
卡魔拉不适合你 奎尔
Gamora is not the one for you, Quill.
怎么哪都有你
Damn shadow.
这全宇宙有两种人
There are two types of beings in the universe.
跳舞的和不跳舞的
Those who dance and those who do not.
我第一次遇见我的爱人是在一场战前动员会
I first met my beloved at a war rally.
- 我的天 - 村里的所有人都在手舞足蹈
- Oh god. - Everyone in the village flailed about dancing.
除了一个女人 我的奥薇特
Except one woman. My Ovette.
我对她一见钟情
I knew immediately she was the one for me.
纵使播放着这世间最美的旋律
The most melodic song in the world could be playing..
她也毫不动容
She wouldn't even tap her foot.
连脚趾头也不动一下
Wouldn't move a muscle.
看起来像是死了
One might assume she was dead.
听起来很棒棒哦
That does sound pretty hot.
搞得我当时就性趣盎然了
It would make my nether- regions engorged.
好了 我明白了
Okay I get it, yes.
我爱跳舞 可卡魔拉不喜欢
I'm a dancer, Gamora is not.
你只需要找一个和你一样
You just need to find a woman who is pathetic,
无可救药的女人就好
like you.
我饿了 给我些那种雅若果根
I'm hungry. Hand me some of that Yaro root.
不行 还没熟透
no its not ripe yet
- 而且我恨你 - 你恨我
- And I hate you. - You hate me?
是你偷了宝石之后把我丢在那儿
You left me there while you stole that stone for yourself.
可你还好好的 还成了女英雄
And yet here you stand, a hero.
我会解开这个锁铐 然后杀了你
I will be free of these shackles soon and I will kill you.
- 我发誓 - 不可能
- I swear. - No.
你的下半辈子会一直在赞达尔的监狱里度过
You're gonna live out the rest of your days in a prison on Xandar,
可怜巴巴地期盼着自己能挣脱锁铐
wishing you could.
真奇怪 一支君王星的舰队朝我们追了过来
This is weird. We've got a Sovereign fleet approaching from the rear.
- 为什么 - 或许因为火箭偷了他们的电池
- Why would they do that? - Perhaps because Rocket stole some of their batteries.
老哥
Dude!
好吧 他没有偷那些东西
Right. He didn't steal some of those.
我不知道他们为什么要追我们 真奇怪
I don't know why they're after us. What a mystery this is.
你脑子里在想什么
What were you thinking?
兄弟 那玩意儿太好偷了
Dude, they were really easy to steal!
你就这么解释呀 拜托
That's your defense? - Come on!
你也瞧见那女妖怪是怎么对我们讲话的了
You saw how that High Priestess talked down to us.
我只是给她一个教训
Now I'm teaching her a lesson!
哦 我没想到原来你还有这么无私的动机呢
Oh, I didn't realize your motivation was altruism.
君王星的人居然误解了你的意图 真是太不像话了
It's really a shame the Sovereign have mistaken your intentions...
- 现在居然还想来杀我们 - 就是嘛
- and are trying to kill us. - Exactly!
- 我在讽刺你 - 不
I was being sarcastic!! - No!
那你应该语气应该说的更像一点
You're supposed to use the sarcastic tone!
- 我现在看起来蠢到家了 - 你们能待会儿再吵吗
- Now I look foolish! - Can we put the bickering on hold...
至少等我们打完这场太空大战
'til after we've survived this massive space battlel?
- 又来一堆 - 太棒了
- More incoming! - Good!
我正想杀人呢
I want to kill some guys!
你一个都杀不了
You're not killing anyone.
这些都是遥控飞船
All those ships are remotely piloted.
可恶
Dammit!
为何进展如此缓慢 将军
What is the delay, Admiral?
大祭司 那些电池都是易爆物品
High Priestess, the batteries, they are exceptionally combustible...
可以瞬间摧毁整个舰队
and could destroy the entire fleet.
必须惩戒藐视我们家伙
Our concern is their slight against our people.
我们花钱请他们 而他们居然对我们行窃
We hired them and they steal from us.
这是对最高秩序的挑衅
It's heresy of the highest order.
全军出击
All command modules...
格杀勿论
fire with the intent to kill.
告诉我最近的宜居星球
What's the nearest habitable planet?
贝尔和特
It's called Berhert.
- 要跳跃多少次 - 只用一次
- How many jumps? - Only one.
但最近的接入口在47光闪之外
But the access point is 47 clicks away.
而且你还得穿过一个小行星带
And you have to go through that quantum asteroid field.
奎尔 要穿越这个
Quill, to make it through that...
必须得是全宇宙最棒得飞行员才行
you'd have to be the greatest pilot in the universe.
算我们走运
Lucky for us...
- 我 - 我就是
- I... - I am.
- 你在干什么 - 我10岁就在开这艘飞船了
- What are you doing? - I've been flying this rig since I was 10 years old.
我还考过宇宙飞船驾驶工程师呢
I was cybernetically engineered to pilot a spacecraft.
你考过傻叉工程师
You were cybernetically engineered to be a douchebag!
- 住嘴 - 奎尔 到晚上后半夜
- Stop it! - Quill, later on tonight,
你准备睡觉的时候 可能会觉得枕头里面有点湿湿的
you're gonna be laying down in your bed and there's gonna be something squishy in your pillowcase.
你会惊讶 这是什么玩意儿 因为我在里边放了粑粑
And you're gonna be like, What's this? And it's gonna be because I put a turd in there.
你敢在我床上拉粑粑 我削了你
You put your turd in my bed, I shave you.
那可不是我的粑粑 我放德拉克斯的
Oh, it won't be my turd. It'll be Drax's.
我的粑粑是绝对宇宙级的
I have famously huge turds.
我们都快死了 你们竟然还在胡扯
We're about to die, and this is what we're discussing?
我擦
Son of a...!
伙计 认真的
Dude! Seriously!
让我来
Hey, let me...
一群蠢货
Idiots!
啊 让奎尔开飞船的下场就是这样
Ah! That's what you get when Quill flies.
还有君王星的飞船在我们屁股后边
We still have a Sovereign craft behind us.
武器失灵了
Our weapons are down.
还差20光闪
Twenty clicks to the jump.
稳住
Hold on.
还没有熟透
It's not ripe.
太空服 用以紧急情况或是找乐子
SPACESUITS FOR EMERGENCY OR FOR FUN.
加油 扎拉克 你可以的
Come on, Zylak. You can do this.
好
Yes!
10光闪后跳跃
15 clicks to the jump!
10光闪
10 clicks!
去死吧 该死的飞船
Die, spaceship!
- 你太差了 扎拉克 - 垃圾
- You suck, Zylak. - Typical.
还有5光闪
It's 5 clicks!
龟儿子
Son of a...!
他们包围了整块区域
They went around the field!
有人把我们的飞船全毁了
Someone destroyed all our ships!
什么
What?
谁
Who?
最后一光闪
1 click!
- 这是什么鬼 管它呢
- What is that? - Who cares?
- 这是虫洞入口 - 快 快
- That's the jump point! Go, go!
那儿有个人
It's a guy.
哦 我的天 他还在外面
Oh my god. He's still out there?
格鲁特 系好安全带
Groot, put your seatbelt on!
做好心理准备 我们要进行一次很垃圾的着陆了
Prepare for a really bad landing!
博赫特星球
BERHERT
这真是太好了
That was awesome!
太好了
Yes!
看看
Look at this!
我们的飞船 另一半去哪了
Where's the other half of our ship?
是我的飞船
My ship.
要是你们用脑子思考而不是用下半身思考的话
Either one of you could've gotten us through that field...
你们两个随便哪个都可以带我们穿过那里
had you flown with what's between your ears instead of what's between your legs!
要是我下半身有只手的话
If what's between my legs had a hand on it...
我都可以保证用那只手让我们安全着陆
I guarantee I could've landed this ship with it.
彼得 因为你的不自量力 我们差点都死了
Peter. We almost died because of your arrogance.
不 是因为他偷走了安纽拉斯电池
No, like, because he stole... Anulax batteries.
是傻不啦叽电池
They're called Harbulary batteries.
不 才不是
No, they're not!
你知道我为什么这么做吗 星嚼
You know why I did it, Star- Munch? Hmm?
我懒得理你
I'm not gonna answer to Star- Munch.
- 因为我想这么做 - 智障
I did it because I wanted to! - Dick.
我们为什么要谈这个
What are we even talking about this for?
有个小矮人摧毁了50艘飞船 救了我们
We just had a little man save us by blowing up 50 ships!
- 多矮 - 我 我不确定 这么矮
- How little? - I, I don't know, like this?
一个一英寸的人救了我们
A little one- inch man saved us?
好吧 如果再靠近点看 我觉得他应该会高得多
Well, if he got closer, I'm sure he'd be much larger.
远小近大 你这只蠢浣熊
That's how eyesight works, you stupid raccoon.
别叫我浣熊
Don't call me a raccoon!
不好意思 我说得不够准确
I'm sorry. I took it too far.
我应该说垃圾小熊猫
I meant trash panda.
这是好话吗
Is that better?
我也不知道
I don't know.
这是坏话 不能再坏了
It's worse. It's so much worse.
你个龟儿子
You son of a...!
我受够你了
I've about had it with you!
有人跟着你穿过虫洞了
Someone followed you through the jump point.
放开我 我会帮你们的
Set me free. You'll need my help.
我们又不傻 星云
I'm not a fool, Nebula.
你就是傻 不然怎么会插手这场战斗
You are a fool to deprive yourself a hand in combat.
- 一旦放了你 你就会袭击我 - 不 我不会
- You'll attack me the moment I let you go. - No I won't.
你应该知道一个穷凶极恶的恶棍通常都会学习如何撒谎
You would think an evil super- villain would learn how to properly lie.
我敢打赌一定是那个一英寸高的人
I bet it's the one- inch man.
这么多年 总算找到你了
After all these years, I've found you.
你到底是谁
And who the hell are you?
看来我帅气的络腮胡让你都认不出我了
I figured my rugged good looks would make that obvious.
我是伊戈
My name is Ego.
我是你爹 彼得
And I'm your dad, Peter.
康特拉夏星
CONTRAXIA
你知道别人都怎么说吗
You know what they say.
不变成鸭子就不会走运
You're out of luck until you've gone duck.
勇度
Yondu!
快下来
Come on down!
我最后和她结婚了
This woman, I ended up marrying her.
听我说 艾丽塔 我爱你
I said, Aleta, I love you...
但是你已经疯了
but you're losing your mind!
她一直都是这样
And she's always been this way.
我再也不能相信她了 你懂的
I could never trust her, you know.
斯塔卡
Stakar.
好久不见
It's been some time.
看来来这个地方真不是个正确的决定
Seems like this establishment is the wrong kind of disreputable.
- 斯塔卡 这里有100个掠夺者帮派
- Stakar. - There's 100 Ravager factions.
你只为了当其中一个的走狗就失去了其他99个机会
You just lost the business of 99 of them by serving one.
- 求你了 先生 求求你 - 你给我走开
- Please, sir. Please! - Get away from me.
你去死吧
You can go to hell then!
老子才不需要你对我指手划脚
I don't give a damn what you think of me!
那你还跟着我们干什么
So, what are you following us for?
你闭嘴 听我说
You're gonna listen to what I gotta say!
我什么都不听 是你背叛了我们的原则
I don't gotta listen to nothing! You betrayed the code!
掠夺者从不贩卖小孩
Ravagers don't deal in kids!
我告诉过你了 我根本不了解情况
I told you before! I didn't know what was going on!
你不知道是因为你根本不想去知道 那样你就可以从中获利
You didn't know 'cause you didn't want to know 'cause it made you rich.
我需要一席之地
I demand a seat at the table.
我和你一样 有这样的雄心壮志
I wear these flames, same as you.
虽然你打扮得和我们一样
You may dress like us...
但当你死去的时候 自由的号角不会为你吹响 勇度
but you'll never hear the Horns of Freedom when you die, Yondu.
掠夺者葬礼的荣光
And the Colors of Ogord...
也不会在你坟墓旁闪耀
will never lash over your grave.
如果你以为
If you think...
我很乐意流放你的话
I take pleasure in exiling you...
你就错了
you're wrong.
你伤了我们所有人的心
You broke all our hearts.
可怜虫
Pathetic.
首先 奎尔背叛了我们
First, Quill betrays us...
而勇度却让他逍遥法外
and Yondu just lets him go scot- free.
我们跟随他
We followed him...
因为他是个敢做敢为的人
because he was the one who wasn't afraid to do what needed to be done.
看来他心软了
Seems he's going soft.
就算他心软了 你在这儿嚼什么舌根
If he's so soft, why are you whispering for?
你明知道我说得没错 克拉格林
You know I'm right, Kraglin.
你最好小心点
You best be very careful
你在船长背后说他坏话
what you say about our captain.
那是谁
Who is that?
勇度 乌冬塔
Yondu Udonta.
我有个建议给你
I have a proposition for you.
你母亲去世后 我让勇度来接你
I hired Yondu to pick you up when your mother passed away.
但是 他没把你还给我
But, instead of returning you...
而是把你留在身边
Yondu kept you.
我不明白为什么
I have no clue as to why.
好吧 我来告诉你为什么
Well, I'll tell you why.
因为我是个瘦小的孩子 我可以钻进大人们进不去的地方
'Cause I was a skinny little kid who could squeeze into places adults couldn't.
这样可以方便行窃
It made it easier for thieving.
我从那时一直都在找你
Well. I've been trying to track you down ever since.
我还以为勇度才是你老爸
I thought Yondu was your father.
什么 我们在一起这么久以来
What? We've been together this whole time...
你一直都以为我和勇度有血缘关系
and you thought Yondu was my actual blood relative?
- 你们长得很像啊 - 勇度是蓝色的
- You look exactly alike. - One's blue!
不 他才不是我父亲
No, he's not my father!
勇度拐走了我
Yondu is the guy who abducted me.
他总把我打出翔 好让我学会反击和战斗
Kicked the crap out of me so I could learn to fight.
还老是恐吓我说要吃掉我
And kept me in terror by threatening to eat me.
- 吃掉你 - 是啊
- Eat you? - Yeah.
啊 真是个狗娘养的
Ah, that son of a bitch!
你是怎么知道我们在这儿的
How did you locate us now?
这个嘛 无论我走到哪里
Well, even where I reside, out past the edge what's known...
我都会听到一个叫星爵的人传奇故事
we've heard tales about the man they call Star- Lord.
我们现在就走吧 怎么样
What say we head out there right now?
也欢迎你的伙伴们过来
Your associates are welcome.
这只三角形脸的猴子也可以来
Even that triangle- face monkey, there.
我向你保证
I promise you...
这里不同于你以前见过的任何地方
it's not like any other place you've ever seen.
在这里
And there,
我能给予你独一无二的遗产
I can explain your very special heritage.
做一个我一直都想做的好父亲
Finally get to be the father I've always wanted to be.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我先去尿个尿
I've gotta take a whiz.
我才不买他的账
I'm not buying it.
走去散散步吧
Let's go take a walk.
我是曼迪斯
I am Mantis.
你干什么
What are you doing?
微笑
Smiling.
我听说这样就能让别人喜欢你
I hear it is the thing to do to make people like you.
但你这样笑别人就不会喜欢你
Not if you do it like that.
哦 我从小一个人在伊戈的星球长大
Oh. I was raised alone on Ego's planet.
我并不懂复杂的人际交往
I do not understand the intricacies of social interaction.
我能摸摸你的小狗吗
Can I pet your puppy?
它太可爱了
It's adorable.
可以
Yes.
有种东西叫做 恶作剧
That is called a practical joke!
我喜欢
I liked it very much!
我刚才就整了一出
I just made it up.
别闹了
Give me a break!
这么长时间以来一直杳无音讯 现在他突然之间冒出来
After all this time, you're gonna show up and just all of a sudden...
说想想成为我父亲 - 我明白
you want to be my dad? - I hear you.
仔细想想 这可能是个陷阱
You know, by the way, this could be a trap.
克里人 秘鲁人 掠夺者 他们都想要我们的命
Ok? The Kree Perus, the Ravagers, they all want us dead.
我知道 但是 - 但是什么
I know, but... - But what?
你还记得你给我讲过扎度 哈斯勒夫吗
What was that story you told me about Zardu Hasselfrau?
谁 - 他有一艘魔法船
Who? - He owned a magic boat.
- 你说大卫 哈塞尔霍夫 - 是啊
- David Hasselhoff? - Right.
不是魔法船 -是辆会说话的汽车
Not in a magic boat. A talking car.
他说过什么
Why did he talk, again?
让我帮他抓犯人 并且拥护他
To help him fight crime, and to be supportive.
你小时候会收藏他的照片
As a child, you would carry his picture in your pocket...
然后告诉别的孩子
and you would tell all the other children...
他是你爸爸 但是他不在你身边
that he was your father, but that he was out of town..
他在和霹雳游侠战斗 或者在德国进行乐队巡演
Shooting Knight Rider or touring with his band in Germany.
我那时说的是醉话 你提这个干什么
I told you that when I was drunk. Why are you bringing it up now?
- 我喜欢这个故事 - 我讨厌这个故事
- I love that story. - I hate that story.
这是个悲伤的故事
It's so sad!
当我还是个小孩 我经常看到别的孩子和爸爸一起玩抛球游戏
As a kid, I used to see all the other kids all playing catch with their dad.
我也想玩 比任何事都想
And I wanted that, more than anything in the world.
这就是我想说的 彼得
That's my point, Peter.
所以他为什么不可以是你的哈塞尔霍夫
What if this man is your Hasselhoff?
听着 如果他干坏事
Listen. If he ends up being evil...
我们杀了他就是
we'll just kill him.
你让这只狐狸守着我
You're leaving me with that fox?
他不是狐狸
He's not a fox.
如果她有什么异样或者你就想打她玩
Shoot her if she does anything suspicious.
你开枪就是了 - 好
Or if you feel like it. - Okay.
嘿 就几天而已
Hey. It'll be just a couple of days.
一旦火箭修好了飞船我马上就回来
We'll be back before Rocket's finished fixing the ship.
如果君王星的人来了呢
What if Sovereign come?
他们不可能知道我们在这里 走吧
There's no way for them to know we're here. Let's go.
我不确定分头行动是不是上策
I'm uncertain about parting ways.
天哪 你跟老太太一样磨叽
God, you're like an old woman.
因为我比较明智吗
Because I'm wise?
你带这么多行李干嘛
Why do you have so much luggage?
我可不想让格鲁特乱玩我的东西
I don't want Groot playing with my things.
我希望你老爸不是个像你一样的大傻叉
I hope daddy isn't as big of a dick as you,
孤儿
Orphan Boy.
你到底想干什么
What is your goal here?
让每个人都讨厌你吗
To get everbody to hate you?
那么你的目的达到了
Because it's working.
嘿 我想问你个私人问题吗
Hey. Can I ask you a personal question?
哦 还从没有人问过我私人问题
Oh! No one has ever asked me a personal question.
你头上的天线是做什么用的
Your antennae, what are they for?
做什么用
Their purpose?
对 我和奎尔打了个赌
Yes, Quill and I have a bet.
- 呃 你怎么说出来了 - 我跟他打赌说
Ugh. You're not supposed to say that. - I say...
当你穿过高度不够的门的时候
that if you're about to go through a doorway that's too low...
那个天线能使你免于被斩首
the antennae will feel this and keep you from being decapitated.
没错 而如果是除了
Right. And if it's anything other than...
保护你免于被门梁斩首的其他用途话
you specifically not being decapitated by a doorway,
就算我赢
I win.
它们不是为了感知门梁的
They are not for feeling doorways.
我认为
I think...
它们跟我拥有的移情能力有关
they have something to do with my empathic abilities.
那是什么能力
What are those?
如果我触碰某个人
If I touch someone,
我能感知他们的感受
I can feel their feelings.
- 能读心 - 不
- You read minds? - No.
心灵感应探知想法
Telepaths know thoughts.
移情能力感知感受
Empaths feel feelings.
感情
Emotions.
我能试试吗
May I?
哦 可以
Oh, all right.
你心中有爱
You feel love.
对啊 我大概对所有人都大爱无边把
Yeah, I guess feel a general unselfish love for just about everybody...
不是的
No!
- 是浪漫的 性爱 - 啥 不不 我不是这样的
- Romantic, sexual love. - No, no, I don't.
- 是对她的爱 - 不是的
- For her! - No!
不是这样
That is not...
好吧
Okay.
她刚刚告诉了所有人你最深藏的肮脏小秘密
She just told everyone your deepest, darkest secret!
兄弟 拜托 我觉得你真有点反应过度了
Dude, come on, I think you're overreacting a little bit.
你一定尴尬死了吧
You must be so embarrassed!
试试我 来 我也要
Do me! Do me! Do me!
我从没感知过这样的喜感
I have never felt such humor.
一点都不好玩
So unbelievably not cool.
你敢碰我 就等着下巴被揍烂吧
Touch me, and the only thing you're gonna feel is a broken jaw.
我某种程度上还能改变感情
I can also alter emotions, to some extent.
是吗 怎么改
Yeah, like what?
如果我触摸一个忧伤的人
If I touch someone who is sad...
我可以短暂地缓和忧伤感
I can ease them into contentment for a short while.
我能让固执的人顺从
I can make a stubborn person compliant.
但我主要用这种能力帮我的主人睡眠
But I mostly use it to help my master sleep.
他晚上想着他的后代 难以成眠
He lies awake at night thinking about his progeny.
在我身上用这种能力
Do one of those on me.
睡吧
Sleep.
没有你那些玩具 你也不是很难对付
Ain't so tough now, without all your toys.
不是吗
Are ya?
行动
Move!
真倒霉
Crap.
- 喂 你好啊 臭老鼠 - 过得怎么样啊 蓝傻蛋
- Hey there, rat!! - How's it going, you blue idiot?
还不错
Not so bad.
我们找到了一个好玩的小乐子
We got ourselves a pretty good little gig here.
一个自大的金发女
This golden gal with quite a high opinion of herself...
给了很多赏金要我们把你和你朋友送到她那里
has offered us a large sum to deliver you and your pals over to her...
因为她想要你们的命
'cause she wants to kill y'all.
你的朋友
Your Friend...
他们人太多了
There's too many of them.
他需要我的帮助 要是你在乎他的话
He needs my help. If you care about him...
那就帮我弄掉这些枷锁
you need to get me out of these bonds.
他们会杀了他的
They are going to kill him!
我得告诉你 找到你可真简单
I'll tell you, it was pretty easy to find you.
在你们和赞达尔星作战的时候 我在你的船上
I put a tracer on your ship back there...
放了追踪器
during the war with Xandar.
向我保证你不会伤害格鲁特
Give me your word you won't hurt Groot...
我就告诉你能量电池在哪里
and I'll tell you where the batteries are.
算你走运 我说话从来算不得数
Lucky for you, my word don't mean squat.
否则 我就真把你交过去了
Otherwise, I'd actually hand you over.
否则 你说什么
Otherwise... what?
我们拿能量电池
We'll take them batteries.
在公开市场中 这些值25万吧
They're worth, what, a quarter mil on the open market?
那个女祭司可是开价一百万啊
That Priestess offered us a million.
25万才是三分之一啊
A quarter is only one third of that!
不是三分之一
A quarter ain't a third.
100万四分之一是25万
A quarter is 25.
25万还不够买双靴子的呢
We can't even buy a pair of boots with 25 units.
够了 重点在于 我们还没有蠢到
Enough! The point is, we ain't stupid enough
当杀银河护卫队的帮凶
to help kill the Guardians of the Galaxy!
那是跟整个新星军团作对
The whole dang Nova Corps'd be on us.
那样是不对的
That ain't right!
这次我真的要忍不住说了 船长
I just gotta say it this one time, captain.
不管奎尔背叛了你多少次
No matter how many times Quill betrays you...
你都会保护他 好像我们其他人都只算个屁
you protect him like none of the rest of us much matter.
- 我才是一直和你并肩作战的人 - 别这么较真 克拉格林
- I'm the one what sticks up for you!! - Take it easy, Kraglin.
说的太对了 兄弟 他变软弱了
Damn straight, lads. He's gone soft.
我认为是时候换头儿了
I suppose it's time for a change in leadership.
把枪放下
Put your ~gob guns down!
伙计们 一定有办法和平解决的
There must be some kind of peaceful resolution to this, fellas.
或者暴力解决法 只不过我就远远观望了
Or even a violent one, where I'm standing over there.
嗨 小伙子们
Well, hello boys.
真没熟
It's not ripe.
伊戈之星
欢迎你们 来到我的世界
Welcome, everyone, to my world.
哇 你有自己的星球
Wow. You have your own planet?
还好啦 不比你们的月球卫星大
Come on. It's no larger than your Earth's moon.
真谦虚
Humility.
我喜欢
I like it.
我也十分特别谦虚
I, too, am extraordinarily humble.
你坐拥一个星球 还能不穿战甲毁掉
You own a planet and can destroy two dozen spaceships
两打宇宙飞船
without a suit.
你到底是何方神圣
What are you exactly?
我就是传说中的神仙啊 小甜心
I'm what's called a Celestial, sweetheart.
神仙 就像上帝一样的存在吗
A Celestial, like a God?
哦 我就是一个小神 孩子
Oh, a small "g", son.
至少在那些我感到
At least on the days I'm
像德拉克斯一样谦逊的日子里是这样
feeling as humble as Drax.
我不知道我到底自哪里来
I don't know where I came from, exactly.
我记得的第一件事是
The first thing I remember is...
光华摇曳 在宇宙中漫无目的地漂流
flickering. Adrift in the cosmos, utterly...
完全的 极致的 孤独
and entirely alone.
几百万年了
Over millions of years...
我学会了控制周围的分子
I learned to control the molecules around me.
我变得更智慧 更强大
I grew smarter and stronger.
我继续建造
And I continued building from there.
一层一层
Layer by layer...
建造你脚下的这个星球
the very planet you walk on now.
但我渴望更多
But I wanted more.
我渴求
I desired...
意义
meaning.
我想着 宇宙中肯定在哪里
There must be some life out there in the universe...
存在除我之外的生命
besides just me, I thought.
于是 我以找到那生命为己任
And so, I set myself the task of finding it.
我按照想象中的
I created...
生命形态创造
what I imagined biological life to be like...
刻画每一寸细节
down to the most minute detail.
你造了小弟弟么
Did you make a penis?
- 老兄 - 你脑子没病吧
- Dude! - What is wrong with you?
如果他是个星球
If he is a planet,
他怎么跟你妈生了小孩
how could he make a baby with your mother?
他要上了她才行啊
He would smush her!
我 呃 我可不行听我父母是如何
I... ugh! I don't need to hear how my parents...
为什么呢
Why?
每年冬至我爹都会讲他是
My father would tell the story of impregnating my mother
- 怎么把我妈肚子搞大的 - 真够恶心的
- every winter solstice. - That's disgusting.
那是很美的
It was beautiful.
你们地球人有性障碍
You Earthers have hang- ups.
对的 德拉克斯
Yes, Drax.
我有小弟弟
I got a penis.
谢谢你了
Thank you.
而且我的小弟弟还很强
And it's not half bad.
我还有痛觉感知
I also have
和消化系统
pain receptors and a digestive system...
还有其它配套的乱七八糟的东西
and all the accompanying junk.
我想要经历人之所以为人的真谛
I wanted to experience what it truly meant to be human.
我在星群中 不断寻找
As I set out amongst the stars...
直到我找到了
'til I found...
我做追求的
what I sought.
生命
Life.
我在宇宙中从来都不孤独
I was not alone in the universe after all.
你什么时候遇到我母亲的
When did you meet my mother?
就在这不久之后
Not long after.
和梅乐迪丝在一起的时候
It was, with Meredith,
我第一次尝到了爱情的滋味
that I first experienced love.
我叫她小百合
I called her my River Lily.
而那份爱孕育出的 彼得
And from that love, Peter...
就是你
You.
我找你已经找了很久了
I've searched for you for so long.
当我听说一个来自地球的人
And when I heard of a man from Earth...
能够手握无限原石而不死
who held an Infinity Stone in his hand without dying...
我就知道你一定是我所爱女子的儿子
I knew you must be the son of the woman I loved.
如果你真的爱她 那你为什么离开她
If you loved her, why did you leave her?
船长 救救我 求求你
Captain! Help me! Please help!
船长
Captain!
是你把他们引上歧途
You're the one what killed those men...
导致他们死亡
by leading them down the wrong path.
因为你又弱
Because you're weak.
又蠢
And stupid.
现在是掠夺者重新崛起
It's time for the Ravagers...
在新的船长带领下再创辉煌的时候了
to rise once again to glory with a new captain...
电击杀冒脸
Taserface!
不好意思 你的名字是
I'm sorry. Your name is...
电击杀冒脸吗
It's Taserface?
没错
That's right.
你能从脸上射出电击光吗
Do you shoot tasers out of your face?
那是隐喻
It's metaphorical!
隐喻什么
For what?
隐喻着
For...
隐喻着听到它的人
It is a name what strikes fear...
心中射入的恐惧
into the hearts of anyone what hears it!
好
Okay...
好吧 随你怎么说
Okay, Whatever you say.
你闭嘴 你就是下一个
You shut up. You're next.
乌冬塔 我已经等了很久
Udonta, I've been waiting a long time to...
笑什么
What?
对不起 真的对不起
I'm sorry. I am so sorry.
我总是想象你在早上醒来 先生
I just keep imagining you waking up in the morning, sir...
看着镜子 然后无比严肃地对自己说
looking in the mirror and, in all seriousness, saying to yourself...
知道什么名字最酷炫吗
"You know what would be a really kick- ass name?
电击杀冒脸
Taserface!".
我脑子里的画面太好笑了
That's how I hear you in my head!
我再也忍不了了
I can't take it anymore!
那你名字的第二选择是什么
What was your second choice?
阴囊帽吗
Scrotum Hat?
新计划 我们要先杀了你
New plan. We're killing you first.
好吧
Well...
比起一辈子顶个愚钝的
Dying is certainly better
像狗屎一样的脑 还认为
than having to live an entire life...
电击杀冒脸是个酷炫名字 死了可能更好
as a moronic shitbag who thinks Taserface is a cool name.
你今天杀得够多了
That's enough killing for today.
她是灭霸的女儿
She's the daughter of Thanos.
你原来不是挺喜欢虐待这些俘虏的吗
I thought you were the biggest sadist in the galaxy.
那是因为以前父亲会给我报酬
That was when daddy was paying my bills.
大祭司想亲手杀了这狐狸
The Priestess wants to kill the fox herself.
至少在克里人那里
And he has bounties on his head
他的头能值不少钱
in at least 12 Kree provinces.
听清楚
I assure you...
我不是那个没了魔法棒就弱不禁风的老头子
I am not as easy a mark as an old man without his magic stick...
也不是愚蠢的森林野兽
or a talking woodland beast.
我要百分之十的报酬
I want ten percent of the take.
还有件事
And a couple more things.
你那个手要是不好用的话
We got a whole box of hands...
我们这还有一整箱子 - 这手还可以
if that one don't work out. - It is fine.
你 呃 觉得克里人会处决船长吗
You, uh, think them Kree is gonna execute the captain?
克里人总觉得自己很仁慈 不会太痛苦
The Kree consider themselves merciful. It will be painless.
呃 这就是我们最好的飞船了
Well, uh, here it is. It's the best ship we got.
导航里有伊戈所在星球的坐标
The location of Ego's planet in the nav.
一旦我们收到钱会立刻把那百分之十给你的
We'll wire you the ten percent once we's paid.
你要这些钱干什么
What're you gonna do with your share?
小时候 父亲经常会让我和卡魔拉在训练的时候互相搏斗
As a child, my father would have Gamora and me battle one another in training.
每次姐姐赢了我
Every time my sister prevailed...
父亲就会把我身体的一部分改造成机械
my father would replace a piece of me with machinery...
说是为了让我像她一样强大
claiming he wanted me to be her equal.
但她每次都赢
But she won.
一次 一次又一次
Again and again and again,
从来没有饶过我一次
never once refraining.
所以杀了我姐姐之后 我会买一艘
So, after I murder my sister... I will buy a warship
载满毁灭武器的战舰
with every conceivable instrument of death.
我会循着我父亲的气息将他慢慢地撕碎
I will hunt my father like a dog and I will tear him apart slowly...
一片一片的撕碎
piece by piece,
直到他哪怕体会到我每天都要忍受的
until he knows some semblance of the profound and unceasing pain...
那钻心的 无休止的痛苦
I know every single day.
棒
Yeah...
我小时候每天都在考虑买什么项链
I was talking about a pretty necklace.
或者帽子什么的
Or a nice hat, you know.
买一些能让女孩惊呼 哇哦 真好看 的东西
Something to make the other girls go, Ooooh, that's nice.
总之 旅途愉快
Anyways, happy trails.
我母亲跟每个人都说我父亲是外星人
My mother told everyone my father was from the stars.
她有脑瘤 所以人们都认为她有妄想症
She had brain cancer, so everyone thought she was delusional.
- 彼得 - 听着 我很愿意去相信你说的话 真的愿意
- Peter. - Listen, I'd love to believe all of this, I really would,
可你竟忍心让这么一个伟大的女人
But you left the most wonderful woman ever,
孤老病死
to die alone.
我也不想离开你的母亲 彼得
I didn't want to leave your mother, Peter.
如果我不经常回到我的星球
If I don't return regularly to my planet...
那这个星球的未来
and the light within it...
甚至这个星球都会衰败灭亡
this form will wither and perish.
那你为什么没回来 为什么又派勇度
Then why didn't you come back? Why did you send Yondu?
这个罪犯来接走我
A criminal, of all people, to come and to fetch me.
我爱你的妈妈 彼得
I loved your mother, Peter!
我在没有你母亲生命的地球上
I couldn't stand to step foot on an Earth...
不敢停留一刻 你不懂那是什么滋味
where she wasn't living! You can't imagine what that's like!
我很清楚那是什么滋味
I know exactly what that feels like!
我亲眼看着她死去
I had to watch her die!
在我存活的几百万年里
Over the millions and millions of years of my existence...
我犯过许多错 彼得
I've made many mistakes, Peter.
但你从来不是一个错误
But you're not one of them.
给我一个机会 让我成为她所期待的那个好父亲
Please give me the chance to be the father she would want me to be.
这个星球上还有很多东西
There's so much that I need to
我需要教给你
teach you about this planet...
还有星球的未来
and the light within.
它们是你生命的一部分 彼得
They are a part of you, Peter.
你在说什么
What do you mean?
给我你的手 孩子
Give me your hand, son.
这样
Here.
抬起你的手
Hold them like that.
现在
Now,
闭上眼睛集中注意力
close your eyes and concentrate.
将你的精力集中在这个星球的中心
Take your brain to the center of this planet.
没错 没错
Yes! Yes!
没错 - 这是什么
Yes! - What was it?
没关系 放松 集中注意力
It's okay, just relax. Concentrate.
你能做到 再来一次
You can do it. Bring it back.
没错
Yes!
控制住它
Now, shape it.
感受它的力量
Feel that energy.
很好
Yes.
欢迎回家
You're home.
彼得
Peter...
你是怎样来到这个诡异又无聊的星球的
How'd you get to this weird, dumb planet?
伊戈在我还是幼虫的时候发现了我
Ego found me in my larvae state.
我是我们星球上的一个孤儿
Orphan on my homeworld.
他把我当做亲生孩子一样一点点养大
He raised me by hand and kept me as his own.
所以你是宠物吧
So, you're a pet.
应该是
I suppose.
可人们都喜欢可爱的宠物
People usually want cute pets.
为什么伊戈会养一个你这么恶心的
Why would Ego want such a hideous one?
我很恶心吗
I am hideous?
谁看到你都会吓一跳 当然恶心
You are horrifying to look at, yes.
但这也挺好的
But that's a good thing.
如果你这么丑还有人爱上你
When you're ugly and someone loves you...
他们一定是很欣赏你的内在美
you know they love you for who you are.
好看的人从来不知道该信任谁
Beautiful people never know who to trust.
那我应该很庆幸自己这么丑
Well, then I am certainly grateful to be ugly.
这些鱼塘 它们让我想起了
Those pools, they remind me of a time...
在我们的家园 我带我女儿去忘忧湖玩耍
when I took my daughter to the Forgotten Lakes of my homeworld.
她跟你很像
She was like you.
一样恶心吗
Disgusting?
是纯真
Innocent.
德拉克斯
Drax?
有件事我必须要告诉你
There's something I must tell you.
- 怎么了 - 这位恶心的臭虫姑娘是我的新朋友
- What's going on? - This gross bug lady is my new friend.
我在学到了好多东西呢 比如我是一个很丑的宠物
I'm learning many things, like I'm a pet and ugly.
你一点也不丑 德拉克斯
You're not ugly. Drax.
- 你睁大眼睛好好看看 - 曼迪斯
- What are you talking about? - Mantis,
你能带我们四处看看吗
Can you show us where we'll be staying?
为什么这星球上没有其他生物
Why are there no other beings on this planet?
这个星球就是伊戈
The planet is Ego.
一只狗绝对不会让一只跳蚤藏在它的背上
A dog would not invite a flea to live on his back.
可你不就是跳蚤吗
And you're not a flea?
我是有用的跳蚤
I'm a flea with a purpose.
我能改善他的睡眠
I help him sleep.
刚才我出来的时候你要跟德拉克斯说什么
What were you about to say to Drax before I walked out?
没什么
Nothing.
你们的住处在这里
Your quarters are this way.
天一亮我们就把你们交给克里人
We deliver you to the Kree in the morning.
天亮之后你们可就活不了多久了
Neither one of you will last much longer after that.
收到 电击杀冒脸
Okay, Taserface.
帮忙给其他人问个好 就说 嗨 电击杀冒脸
Hey, tell the other guys, we said... "Hi, Taserface."
喔 这个小植物怎么办 我能用石头砸碎它吗
Oh! Hey, what about this little plant? Can I smash it with a rock?
不 杰夫
No, Gef.
树树这么可爱 怎么能杀小树树
It's too adorable to kill.
给它做一件小衣服
Take it to the tailor.
说实话 你的手下都是一群傻吊
No offense, but your employees are a bunch of jerks.
斯塔卡解救我之前
I was a Kree battle slave for 20 years
我当了二十年克里人的战争奴
when Stakar freed me.
他让我成为掠夺者的一员
He offered me a place with the Ravagers.
他告诉我 我只需要遵守组织的纪律
He said, all I needed to do was adhere to the code.
但我那时太年轻
But I was young...
既贪婪又愚蠢
and greedy and stupid.
就像你偷电池的时候
Like you stealing those batteries.
你说的是德拉克斯
That was mostly Drax.
我和斯塔卡 还有其他的队员
Me & Stakar, and the other captains...
就像你和你的朋友们
we weren't so different from you and your friends.
那是我唯一的家
The only family I ever had.
我破了戒以后
When I broke the code...
他们流放了我
they exiled me.
这都是自作自受
This is what I deserve.
别说了 银河大影帝
Slow down, drama queen.
你是自作自受 我不是啊 我们得逃出去
You might deserve this, but I don't. We gotta get out of here.
奎尔呢
Where's Quill?
呃 他去跟老父亲叙旧了
Ah, he went off with his old man.
伊戈 - 没错
Ego? - Yeah.
今天听到的净是些傻比名字
It's a day for dumb- ass names.
你笑了 有那么一瞬间我感到好温暖
You smiled, there for a second, I got a warm feeling.
可你那反胃的牙齿告诉我那是个错觉
But then it was ruined by those disgusting- ass teeth.
你是专业傻逼吗
You're like, a professional asshole, or what?
你说的没错
Pretty much a pro.
你为什么没遵守承诺把奎尔交给伊戈
Why didn't you deliver Quill to Ego like you promised?
他很小
He was skinny.
他能钻进我们大人进不去的地方
He fit into places we couldn't.
很适合做贼
Good for thieving.
我有个办法能帮我们逃出去
I got an idea on how to get out of here.
可需要你那小伙伴的协助
But we're gonna need your little friend.
吉祥物 吉祥物 吉祥物
Mascot! Mascot! Mascot!
兄弟们想看着这腊肠喝醉的样子吗
You fellas all want ~sausage drunk?
它被惹火的时候真是可爱的很
Look how cute it is when it's all riled up.
真是有生之年系列
It's god- dang precious.
喂 嘿 小树苗
Psst! Hey, twig!
过来
Come here.
来啊
Come on.
兄弟 他们对你做了什么
Man. What'd they do to you?
嘿 你想帮我们逃出去吗
Hey, you want to help us get out of here?
我需要你帮我去拿一件东西
There's something I need you to get and bring back to me.
在船长室里有一个鳍状的东西
In the captain's quarters, there's a prototype fin.
本来是戴在我头上的
The thing I wore in my head.
床边有个抽屉
There's a drawer next to the bunk.
就在里面 是红色的
It's in that. It's red.
听懂了吗
You got it?
那是我的内裤
That's my underwear.
我很确定他根本不知道你刚才说了什么
Yeah, I was pretty sure he didn't know what you were talking about.
你得慢慢地耐心解释
You have to explain it more careful.
是鳍一样的东西
It's a prototype fin.
这是只奥伦
That's an Orloni.
是鳍状物 格鲁特
It's a fin, Groot.
再去试一次
You try it this time.
好吧
All right.
这是沃克的眼睛
That's Vorker's eye.
他在睡觉的时候格鲁特把它偷掉了
He takes it out when he sleeps.
- 去 再去找 - 把眼睛留下
- Go, look again. - But leave the eye here.
- 为什么 - 只要他明天一早醒来
- Why? - He's gonna wake up tomorrow...
就会大喊
and he's not gonna know...
我的眼睛在哪
where his eye is!
这是张桌子
That's a desk.
跟你说过它才这么大点
We told you it was this big.
告诉我肯定是你的手下在什么地方
Tell me you guys have a refrigerator somewhere...
藏了一冰箱的脚趾头
with a bunch of severed human toes.
好吧 以后谁也不要再提起这件事
Okay, then let's just agree to never discuss this.
你要找的那个抽屉上面有这个标志
The drawer you want to open has this symbol on it.
记住了吗
Okay?
什么 不对
What? No!
他以为你想让他当成帽子戴在头上
He thinks you want him to wear it as a hat.
我不想让他带什么帽子
That's not what I said!
- 我是格鲁特 - 他听到你这么说松了一口气
- I am Groot! - He's relieved you don't want him to.
- 我是格鲁特 - 他讨厌帽子
- I am Groot. - He hates hats.
我是格鲁特 - 不管谁都不喜欢帽子
I am Groot. - On anyone, not just himself.
- 我是格鲁特 - 上一秒 你以为那家伙脑袋是
- I am Groot? - One minute, you think someone
奇形怪状的 然而下一秒
has a weird shaped head, the next minute,
你才看清楚那不是脑袋是一顶帽子
just because, you realize part of that head is the hat.
这就是你不喜欢帽子的原因吗
That's why you don't like hats?
都到了这个时候了你们还关心这个
This is an important conversation right now?
你在那做什么
What you have there?
当叛徒不是我的本意
I didn't mean to do a mutiny.
但他们把我的朋友都杀了
They killed all my friends.
你让第三救生舱的人做好离开的准备吧
Get the third quadrant ready for release.
哦对了
One more thing.
这船上有奎尔的旧音乐的拷贝吗
You got any clones of Quill's old music on the ship?
他拿到了 勇度拿到他的鳍了
He's got it! Yondu got the fin!
快上啊
Go!
在那下面
Down there!
你这个疯子
You maniac!
这整艘船都要炸了
The whole ship's gonna blow.
倒不是整艘船
Not the whole ship.
- 你是谁 - 我在把勇度的船
- Who is this? - I am sending you the
的坐标发给你
coordinates for Yondu's ship.
- 释放救生舱 - 收到 船长
Release the quadrant! - Aye, captain!
我只要求一点
I only ask one thing.
告诉你们尊贵的祭司
That your High Priestess...
告诉他我的名字
tell him the name of the man what sealed his fate.
电击杀冒脸
Taserface.
- 我们的目标是哪呢 船长 - 伊戈之星
Where to, captain? - Ego.
不是吧
No, boy!
这太不健康了 哺乳动物心跳一次跳五十次才是正常的
It ain't healthy, mammalian body to hop more than 50 jumps at a time.
- 这我知道 - 我们的心跳快到七百了
I know that. - We're about to do 700!
我猜这江山总有一天会是我的吧
So, I guess this could all be mine someday.
火箭 火箭 你还在吗
Rocket? Rocket, are you there?
你在干什么 彼得
What are you doing, Peter?
和我一起跳舞吧
Dance with me.
我才不和你跳舞呢
I'm not going to dance with you.
这是山姆 库克
This is Sam Cooke...
地球史上最伟大的歌手之一
one of the greatest Earth singers of all time.
德拉克斯说你不是一个舞者
Drax says you're not a dancer.
你要是跟谁说起这件事
If you ever tell anyone about this...
我保证会打死你
I will kill you.
我们两个什么时候才能
When are we going to do something
做这件羞羞的事情呢
about this unspoken thing between us?
什么羞羞的事
What unspoken thing?
这个
This...
再见啦 山姆 戴安娜
Cheers, Sam and Diane.
就是那种综艺上一男一女互相嘲讽
Guy and a girl on a TV show who dig each other...
却要为了防止收视率下降而不能说白的
but never say it because the TV ratings would go down...
羞羞的事
sort of thing.
这里没什么不能说的
There's no unspoken thing here.
好吧 这就尴尬了 因为要是你说了这件事就不羞了
Well, it's a catch- 22, because if you said it then it would be spoken...
而你就成骗子了
and you'd be a liar.
因此 你只能通过
So, by not saying it...
不说穿这件事来达到说真话和承认有羞羞的事的目的
you are telling the truth and admitting that there is.
不 这可不是我
No, that's not what I...
我们在此刻讨论的应该是这个地方
What we should be discussing right now is, something about this place.
这里有点奇怪
It doesn't feel right.
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
你是唯一一个想要我来这里的人
You're the one who wanted me to come here.
那个叫曼迪斯的女孩 她在害怕着什么
That girl, Mantis... she's afraid of something.
你为什么总想从从我身边夺走一切
Why are you trying to take this away from me?
- 我不是想 - 他是我的父亲 我的亲人
I'm not trying... - He's my father. He's blood.
你在地球上也有亲人啊 怎么不见你回去
Well you have blood on Earth, you never wanted to return there.
再说一遍 是你强迫我来这的
Again, you made me come here.
而地球 地球是我妈妈在我面前死去的地方
And Earth, Earth is the place where my mother died in front of me.
不 那是因为那是真实的世界 这里只是一个幻境
No, it's because that place is real, and this is a fantasy.
这才是真实的 我只有一半的人类血缘 你懂吗
This is real! I'm only half human, remember?
那一半才是我所担心的
That's the half I'm worried about.
这我懂 你之所以嫉妒
I get it. You're jealous...
是因为我现在是半神了 而你更喜欢比你弱的我
because I'm part god and you like when I'm the weak one.
你真是太无理取闹了
You were insufferable to begin with.
我还没法联系上火箭
I haven't been able to reach Rocket.
我要去外面看看能不能收到信号
I'm going to go outside and try to get a signal.
你猜怎么着 这还真不是那档叫欢呼的综艺
You know what? This is not Cheers after all.
这就是那种有一个人愿意去
This is whatever the show is where one person is willing to...
尝试新机会
open themselves up to new possibilities,
而另一个则是完全不信任其他人的混蛋的综艺
and the other person is a jerk who doesn't trust anybody!
这是一个根本不存在的综艺
It's a show that doesn't exist!
所以这就是为什么这档综艺收视率为零
That's why it would get zero ratings.
我都不懂欢呼是什么综艺
I don't know what Cheers is.
我终于找到自己的家人了
I finally found my family.
你还不懂吗
Don't you understand that?
我还以为我们就是你家人
I thought you already had.
该死
Damn it.
你这个疯子
Psychopath!
你在逗我吗
Are you kidding me!
我赢了
I win.
我在战斗中打赢你了
I win, I bested you in combat.
不 是我救了你的命
No. I saved your life.
那是你太蠢了才会救我
Well you were stupid enough to let me live.
你让我活着
You let me live!
我才不要你总是尝试着想打败我
I don't need you to always try and defeat me!
我才不是那个飞过整个宇宙就是为了赢的人呢
I'm not the one who just flew across the universe just because I wanted to win.
别对我的理想指手画脚
Do not tell me what I want.
我才用不着跟你说呢 这都是明摆着的事
I don't need to tell you what you want! It's obvious!
你才是那个想赢的人 我只想要一个姐姐
You were the one who wanted to win. And I just wanted a sister!
你就是我的一切
You were all I had.
但你也是那个总想赢的人
But you were the one who needed to win.
灭霸弄瞎了我的眼睛
Thanos pulled my eye from my head...
扯掉了我的大脑
and my brain from my skull...
还剁了我的手臂
and my arm from my body...
就因为你
because of you.
你还好吗 孩子
You all right, son?
我看见你女朋友气冲冲的离开了
I saw your girl stomp off a little earlier in quite a huff.
没错
Yeah.
真巧 你在听这首歌
It's fortuitous, you listening to this song.
叫 布兰迪
You know, uh, "Brandy?"
镜子乐队的歌
By Looking Glass?
是你妈妈最喜欢的歌曲之一
A favorite of your mom's.
是的 确实
Yes. Yeah, it was.
地球上最伟大的音乐作品之一
One of Earth's greatest musical compositions.
- 或许是最伟大的 - 没错
- Perhaps its very greatest. - Yeah, yes!
你知道吗 彼得 我们 就是这首歌里的海员
You know, Peter, you and I, we're... we're the sailor in that song.
他在一个夏日到来
He came on a summer's day.
从远方带来礼物
Bringing gifts from far away.
就像我带给你妈妈的那个孩子
Like the child I put in your mother.
以及你带给卡魔拉的自由
Or the freedom you brought Gamora.
布兰迪 你是个好女孩
Brandy, you're a fine girl.
你会成为一位好妻子
What a good wife you would be.
我的妻子 我的爱人
My life, my love,
我的夫人 就是大海
my lady, is the sea.
大海呼唤着船员归来
The sea calls the sailor back.
他爱着那个女孩 但这不是他的归属
And he loves the girl, but that's not his place.
大海呼唤着他 就如历史
The sea calls upon him as history
在呼唤着伟大的人
calls upon great men.
有时我们被剥夺了凡人的乐趣
And sometimes we are deprived the pleasures of mortals.
当然 你或许不是凡人 但我
Well, you may not be mortal, but me...
不 彼得 只要这个星球上还有光
No, Peter. Death will remain a stranger to both of us,
死神就不会接近我们
as long as the light burns in this planet.
我是不死的
I'm immortal?
- 真的吗 - 没错
- Really? - Yes!
只要这里还有光
As long as this light exists.
而我能用这些光去
And I can use the light to
做一些酷的事情 比如
build cool things, like...
你是怎么建造出这一整个星球的
how you made this whole planet?
当你还不熟练的时候
Well, it may take you a few million years of practice...
或许会花上你几百万年的时间去练习 不过 没错
before you get really good at it. But, yes!
这是 准备好建造一座八百英尺的
This is...! Well, get ready for an 800- foot
骷髅王和希瑟 拉克里尔的雕像吧
statue of Pac- Man, with Skeletor and Heather Locklear.
- 你要做什么都行 - 我会做出奇怪的东西的
- Whatever you want. - I'm gonna make some weird shit.
你知道吗 彼得 这可是一个重担
You know, Peter, it is a tremendous responsibility.
只有我们能重塑宇宙
Only we can remake the universe.
只有我们能掌控宇宙的缰绳
Only we can take the bridle of the cosmos...
引导它去该去的地方
and lead it to where it needs to go.
怎么做
How?
跟我来
Come with me.
德拉克斯 德拉克斯 德拉克斯
Drax. Drax. Drax.
德拉克斯 我们该聊聊了
Drax. We need to talk.
对不起 我喜欢骨头上长肉的女人
I'm sorry. But I like a woman with some meat on her bones.
- 什么 - 我只是想委婉的让你明白
- What? - I tried to let you down easily by
- 你很恶心这件事 - 不 我要说的不是这个
- telling you I found you disgusting. - No, that's not why...
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我在想象和你在一起的图景
I'm imagining being with you.
德拉克斯 那可不是 我不喜欢你那么做
Drax, that's not... I don't like you like that.
我都不知道你是什么东西
I don't even know the type of thing you are.
喂 这可没必要演变成私人恩怨啊
Hey! There's no need to get personal.
听着 伊戈已经得到他想要的了
Listen! Ego's gotten exactly what he wanted.
我早就该告诉你了 我就是蠢
I should have told you earlier. I am stupid.
你们都处于险境中
You are in danger.
那是什么
What is that?
现在 你需要重新调整你对待生活的态度了
Now, you need to readjust the way you process life.
我们身边的一切 包括那个女孩
Everything around us, including the girl...
都是暂时的
everything is temporary.
我们才是永恒
We are forever.
永恒不会无聊吗
Doesn't eternity get boring?
有目标就不会无聊 彼得
Not if you have a purpose, Peter.
这就是你在这里的原因
Which is why you're here.
我跟你说了多年前
I told you how all those years ago...
我是如何用一种不断的冲动去寻找生命的
I had an unceasing impulse to find life.
但我没跟你说的是我最终找到了其他生命
But what I did not tell you is how I finally did find it.
但那却让我
It was all so...
很失望
disappointing.
从那时起
And that is when I came...
我就深刻地意识到
to a profound realization.
我与生俱来的渴望去寻找其他生命
My innate desire to seek out other life...
并不是为了让我成为那样的人
was not so that I could walk among that life.
彼得
Peter.
我找到了生命的意义
I have found meaning.
我看见了
I see it.
永生
Eternity.
我的天
Oh, my God.
我们得离开这个星球了
We need to get off this planet.
不管怎样 在我被粗暴地打断之前
Anyway, before I was so rudely interrupted.
在那个时候 我还是个联邦快递员
At that time, I was a Federal Express man.
你在干嘛呢
What the hell you doing, boy?
从你谈论他的方式我能推断 这个伊戈是个大麻烦
I could tell by how you talked about him, this Ego is bad news.
我们在这是为了救奎尔
We are here to save Quill.
但为了什么 为了荣誉 还是为了爱
For what? Huh? For honor? For love?
不 我才不在意那些
No. I don't care about those things.
我想救奎尔是为了证明我比他厉害
I want to save Quill so I can prove I'm better than him!
我以后都能用这件事打击他了
I can lord this over him forever.
你笑我干嘛
What are you laughing at me for?
你能欺骗你自己和别人 但你可骗不了我
Oh, you can fool yourself and everyone else, but you can't fool me.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
你可一点也不了解我 你个屌丝
You do not know anything about me, loser.
我可是非常了解你
I know everything about you.
我知道你装的好像是最刻薄和严厉的人
I know you play like you're the meanest and the hardest...
- 但实际上你才是最胆小的 - 闭嘴
- but actually you're the most scared of all. - Shut up!
我知道你偷了你不需要的电池
I know you steal batteries you don't need...
你赶走了所有受得了你的人
and you push away anyone who's willing to put up with you...
只因为只要一点点爱
Because just a little bit of love...
就能让你记起你内心的空虚和寂寞
reminds you how big and empty that hole inside you actually is.
- 你给我闭嘴 - 我知道那些科学家
- I said, shut up! - I know them scientists that made
- 让你永远不能认清自己 - 我是说真的 伙计
- you never gave a rat's ass about you. - I'm serious, dude.
就像我的亲生父母 把我这个
Just like my own damn parents, who sold me...
亲生孩子卖为奴隶
their own little baby, into slavery.
我知道真实的你是什么样的
I know who you are, boy.
因为你跟我一样
Because you're me.
咱俩算什么组合啊
What kind of a pair are we.
是准备跟一个星球对战的组合
The kinds that's about to go fight a planet, I reckon.
好的 没问题
All right! Okay.
等下
Wait.
跟什么对战
Fight a what?
你们到底是谁 这到底是什么地方
Who are you people? What is this place?
卡魔拉 放开她
Gamora, let her go!
洞穴里的尸骨 都是什么人的
The bodies in the caverns, who are they?
你害怕了
You are scared.
我称之为 扩张
I call it, the Expansion.
这就是我的目标
It is my purpose.
现在
Now,
这也是你的目标
it is yours, as well.
太美了
It's beautiful.
我花了几千年的时间
Over thousands of years...
我在数千个星球里
I implanted thousands of extension of myself...
植入我的分身
on thousands of worlds.
我要完成生命唯一的终极目标
I need to fulfill life's one true purpose...
不断繁衍 不断扩散
to grow and spread...
覆盖整个宇宙
covering all that exists...
直到所有的一切都变成
until everything is...
我
Me.
她刚对我做了什么
What did she do to me?
她已经把一切都告诉我了
She already told me everything.
现在我只有一个问题还没有解决
I only had one problem.
单靠我一个天神族人的力量不足以完成这项伟业
A single Celestial doesn't have enough power for such an enterprise.
但是有两个天神族人的话 恩 现在
But two Celestials... Well, now...
就很有可能了
that just might do.
那些尸体 都是伊戈的后代
The bodies... are his children.
在我所做的一切工作中
Out of all my labors...
最大的骗局就是试着
the most beguiling was attempting to...
把我的DNA跟另一个物种的结合
graft my DNA with that of another species.
我希望能通过结合找到
I hoped the result of such a coupling would be...
足以支持这个扩张计划的力量
enough to power the Expansion.
我以前让勇度给我送来过一些孩子
I had Yondu deliver some of them to me.
虽然这坏了劫掠者的规矩 但是
It broke the Ravager code, but
我给了他足够的报酬 而且
I compensated him generously, and...
为了不让他良心上过不去 我跟他说我不会伤害这些孩子
to ease his conscience, I said I'd never hurt them.
这倒是实话 他们死的时候都很平静
And that was true, they never felt a thing.
但是 一个接一个 都让我失望了
But, one after the other, they failed me.
他们没一个人身上有天神族的基因
Not one of them carried the Celestial genes.
直到你的出生 彼得
Until you, Peter.
在我这么多后代中
Out of all my spawn...
只有你身上散发着神力之光
only you carry the connection to the light.
我们现在得找到彼得 然后赶紧离开这个鬼地方
We need to find Peter now and get off this damn planet.
他现在被伊戈控制在身边
Ego will have brought him to his side by now.
那我们直接走吧 - 不行 他是我们的朋友
Then we just go. - No! He's our friend.
你们整天跟对方吵个不停
All any of you do is yell at each other.
你们不是朋友 - 你说的没错
You're not friends. - You're right.
我们不是朋友 是家人
We're family.
我们绝不抛弃彼此
We leave no one behind.
除了你
Except maybe you.
这么多年以来
For the first time in my existence...
我终于不再是孤单一个人了
I am truly not alone!
怎么了 儿子
What is it, son?
我朋友
My friends.
哦 不 你看 这就是你体内人类的弱点 彼得
Oh, no, you see, that's the mortal in you, Peter.
我们天神族比他们高贵多了
We are beyond such things.
是的
Yes.
现在 - 但是我妈妈
Now... - But my mother...
你说过你爱她
You said you loved my mother.
我确实爱过她
And that I did.
我的小百合她知道收音机里
My River Lily who knew all the words
每一首歌的歌词
to every song that came over the radio.
我回地球看过她三次
I returned to Earth to see her three times.
我知道如果我再回去一次
And I knew if I returned a 4th...
我就舍不得回来了
I'd never leave.
这个扩张计划
The Expansion...
我存在的理由将毁于一旦 所以
the reason for my very existence would be over, so...
我做了我该做的事儿
I did what I had to do.
但
But...
把肿瘤放进她大脑的时候我也很难过
it broke my heart to put that tumor in her head.
什么
What?
好了 好了 我知道这不是个好办法
Now, now, I know that sounds bad.
你以为你自己多厉害吗
Who in the hell do you think you are?
你杀了我母亲 - 我费了这么大劲
You killed my mother! - I tried so hard...
才找到有最佳基因的你
to find the form that best suited you...
你就这样谢我吗
and this is the thanks I get?
你真该学学怎么做人了
You really need to grow up!
我本想让你跟我一起完成这项伟大的事业
I wanted to do this together,
现在我看你以后1000年 只能当个供给
but I suppose you'll have to learn by spending the next 1000 years
来给我提供神力了
as a battery!
终于好了 火箭
Finally. Rocket?
把发射器放身边 我好找到你
Keep that transmitter nearby so I can find you.
我们现在在一个老旧的飞行器里 维普和勇度
We're in an old piece of construction Wip and Yondu once used
以前开着它抢过阿斯科瓦瑞银行
to slice open the bank of A'askavaria.
伊戈疯了 - 我知道 准备好
Ego's unhinged. - I know. Get ready.
动手吧 克拉格林
Drop it, Kraglin.
不
No.
我的生命 我的姑娘
My life, my love,
但我爱的是大海
my lady is the sea.
彼得
Peter.
这就是我的大海
This is the sea.
这儿呢 混蛋
Hey there, jackass!
那是什么东西
What is that thing?
快闪开 格鲁特小蠢树
Out of the way, dumber, smaller Groot!
我早告诉过你不太对劲儿
I told you something didn't feel right.
早告诉过你 这是我现在最不想听到的话
I told you so? It's just what I hate to hear right now.
我不是回来了吗 - 因为我们之前有一种妙不可言的东西
I came back, didn't I? - Because of our unspoken thing.
胡扯 没有这种东西
There's no unspoken thing.
你干嘛呢 你差点把我们都杀了
What are you doing? You could've killed us all.
啊 你是说谢谢你 火箭 - 我们都摆平了
"Ahn... Thank you, Rocket"? - We had it under control.
并没有 那只是伊戈的一个分身
We did not. That is only an extension of his true self.
他很快还会回来的
He'll be back soon.
- 蓝妹妹怎么在这儿 - 我只想搭个便车赶紧回家
- What's Smurfette doing here? - Whatever I need to get a damn ride home.
- 她想杀了我 - 我救了你 你个蠢狐狸
- She tried to murder me! - I saved you, you stupid fox!
他不是狐狸 - 我是格鲁特
He's not a fox. - I am Groot.
我也不是 完熊 - 我是格鲁特
I'm not a "rabboon" either. - I am Groot.
浣熊 行了吧
Raccoon. Whatever.
我们怎么消灭一个天神族 - 他有一个中枢
How do we kill a Celestial? - There's a center to him.
大脑 灵魂 什么的 被一种保护壳包裹着
His brain, his soul, whatever it is, in some sort of protective shell.
在地面下的洞穴中
It's in the caverns below the surface.
勇度
Yondu?
推进器坏了
Thrusters are out.
我是不是得庆幸小时候又小又瘦
Guess I should be glad I was a skinny kid,
不然你早把我送给这个疯子了
otherwise you woulda delivered me to this maniac.
你到现在还以为我是因为这才把你留下的吗 蠢货
You still reckon that's the reason I kept you around, you idiot?
你就是这么跟我说的啊 你个老蠢货
That's what you told me, you old doofus.
我是无意中发现了那些孩子的下场
Well once I figured out what happened to them other kids...
所以我决定把你留下了 - 你以前还说要把我吃了
I wasn't gonna hand you over. - You said you were gonna eat me.
那样说是为了好玩嘛 - 我可不觉得好玩
That was being funny! - Not to me!
你们有问题亟待解决啊
You people have issues.
我当然有问题
Well of course I have issues.
我亲爹竟然是这种怪物
That's my freaking father!
推进器好了
Thrusters are back up.
我们是不是该往上飞啊 - 不行
We should be going up! - We can't.
既然我们知道了伊戈想摧毁整个宇宙
Ego wants to eradicate the universe as we know it.
我们就得把他灭了
We have to kill him.
火箭 - 好
Rocket! - Yup!
我们是又要拯救银河系了吗
So we're saving the galaxy again?
我猜是的 - 酷毙了
I guess. - Awesome!
我们要是能救银河系两次
We're really gonna be able to jack up our price
身价铁定要升啊
if we're 2- time galaxy saving.
真不敢相信你就这么点儿追求
I seriously can't believe that's where your mind goes.
我也就想想 伙计 我以为我们是朋友呢
It was just a random thought, man. I thought we were friends?
我当然不止这么点儿追求 我当然关心星球啊 建筑啊
Of course, I care about the planets and the buildings...
还有星球上所有的动物啊
and all the animals on the planets.
还有星球上的人
And the people.
那个暴躁的小宠物好可爱啊 我都要被他逗死了
The crabby puppy's so cute. He makes me want to die!
汤 汤
Soup! Soup!
全体 发射小型飞行器
Pilots, release envoy units.
传感器探测到星球地表下有电池
Our sensors detect a battery below the surface of the planet.
俯冲
Dive!
船长
Cap'n?
说说 为啥伊戈让你来这儿
Tell me, why did Ego want you here?
他需要我的体内的神力之光
He needs my genetic connection
帮他摧毁整个宇宙
to the light to help destroy the universe.
他还想教我怎么控制这种力量
He tried to teach me how to control the power.
你学会了吗 - 一点点
So could you? - A little.
我弄出了个小球 - 球
I made a ball. - A ball?
我使出所有力气控制我的意念
I thought as hard as I could.
结果只弄出了个球 - 用你的意念哈
It was all that I can come up with. - You thought?
你以为我是光用想的
You think when I make this arrow fly,
让我的箭飞起来的吗
that I use my head?
在那儿 伊戈的中枢
There. That's Ego's core.
那中枢很厚 火箭 - 知道了
That core is thick, Rocket. - I got it covered.
我们得赶紧
We must hurry.
用不了多久伊戈就能找到我们了
It will not take Ego long to find us.
稳住
Keep it steady.
我们把他引到中心然后杀了他
We draw him to the center then we kill him.
船长 - 出什么事儿了 克拉格林
Cap'n? - What is it, Kraglin?
嘿 记得那个叫艾伊莎的小妞吗 - 记得 咋了
Hey, remember that Ayesha chick? - Yeah, why?
哦 我去
Oh, hell!
你为啥不发射激光
Why aren't you firing the lasers?
发电机会爆炸的
They blew up the generator.
我应该带了一个小雷管
I think I packed a small detonator.
没有炸药光有雷管没用
A detonator is worthless without explosives.
我们有这些电池
Well, we got these.
这玩意儿能杀死伊戈吗
Is that thing strong enough to kill Ego?
如果能的话 可以在他整个神经系统里产生连锁反应
If it is, it will cause a chain reaction throughout his entire nervous system.
- 所以呢 - 整个星球都会爆炸
- Meaning what? - The entire planet will explode.
我们得离开这 越快越好
We'll have to get out of here, fast.
我弄了个定时器
I rigged the timer.
走
Go!
他来了
He's coming!
你不是说你能让他睡着吗
Didn't you say you can make him sleep?
只有在他想睡的时候 他太强了
When he wants. He's too powerful!
我办不到
I can't!
你必须相信你自己
You will have to believe in yourself.
因为我相信你
Because I believe in you.
睡觉
Sleep!
没想到她能成功
I never thought she'd be able to do it...
看起来弱不禁风的
with as weak and skinny as she appears to be.
我不知道我能让他睡多久
I don't know how long I can hold him!
金属太厚了
The metal's too thick.
要想炸弹起作用 我们得把它放在伊戈中枢的位置
For the bomb to work, we actually need to place it on Ego's core.
但是咱们膀大腰圆的根本没法钻进那个小洞里
And our fat butts ain't gonna fit through those tiny holes.
好吧
Well...
这方法不太好吧
That's a terrible idea.
这也是唯一的方法了
Which is the only kind of idea we have left.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
火箭 做这个 火箭 做那个
"Rocket, do this.", "Rocket, do that."
今天都什么事儿啊
What a day.
好的 先拨这个开关 在拨这个开关
All right. First, you flip this switch, then this switch.
这样就激活了
That activates it.
然后你再按这个按钮
Then you push this button.
然后你有五分钟的时间逃跑
Which will give you five minutes to get out of there.
听好 不管怎样
Now, whatever you do...
千万别按这个
Don't push this button.
按下它炸弹会立刻爆炸 然后我们就都死定了
Because that would set off the bomb immediately and we'll all be dead.
好了 重复一遍我刚说的话
Now, repeat back what I just said.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
- 我是格鲁特 - 没错
- I am Groot. - That's right.
- 我是格鲁特 - 别!!!
- I am Groot. - No!
不对 这个按钮会把我们都炸死的!!!
No, that's the button that will kill everyone!
再来一遍
Try again.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
- 我是格鲁特 - 不 这跟你刚说的一毛一样好吗???!!!
- I am Groot. - No! That's exactly what you just said,
他怎么可能完的成呢
how is that even possible?
你应该按哪个按钮 指给我看
Which button is the button you're supposed to push? Point to it.
不是!!!
No!
你这样他会更紧张的
Hey, you're making him nervous!
闭嘴 给我找点胶带来
Shut up and give me some tape!
外面有谁带了胶带吗 我想把那个按钮粘上
Does anybody have any tape out there? I wanna put some tape over the death button.
我没有胶带 我去问问
I don't have any tape. Let me check.
喂 勇度
Yo, Yondu!
你有 嗷 你那儿有胶带吗
Do you have any... ouch! Do you have any tape?
卡魔拉 你有胶带吗
Gamora? You have the tape?
胶带
Tape!
算了没事儿
Ah, never mind.
德拉克斯 你有胶带吗
Drax? Do you have any tape?
嗯 透明胶也可以
Yeah, Scotch tape would work.
没有那你问我能不能用干什么
Then why did you ask me if Scotch tape would work if you don't have any?
没人有胶带
Nobody has any tape!
- 就没有一个人带着胶带吗 - 没
- Not a single person has tape? - Nope.
- 你问星云了吗 - 当然
- Did you ask Nebula? - Yes!
你确定
Are you sure?
我问勇度的时候她就坐在他旁边啊
I asked Yondu and she was sitting right next to him.
我就知道你在撒谎
I knew you're lying!
你包里不但有无价的电池 还有原子弹
You have priceless batteries and an atomic bomb in your bag.
你才最有可能有胶带好吗
If anybody's gonna have tape, it's you!
这就是问题所在啊 所有的事情都得我来做
That's exactly my point! I have to do everything!
你这是浪费时间
You are wasting a lot of time here!
我们死定了
We're all gonna die.
后推进器又坏了了
Ah, rear thrusters are out again!
没有发电机我们就完蛋了
We're done for without that generator!
守护者们
Guardians.
这句话可能会让你们有所安慰
Perhaps it will provide you solace...
你们的死不是没有意义的
that your deaths are not without purpose.
这会对想背叛我们的人 起到杀鸡儆猴的作用
They will serve as a warning for all of those tempted to betray us.
别招惹君王星人
Don't screw with the Sovereign.
会很疼的
This is gonna hurt.
费什么话
Promises, promises.
不
No!
不 不 不!!!
No! No! Noooo!
飞船要爆炸了
We're gonna blow!
彼得 不要
Peter! No!
怎么了
What?
你现在看起来很像玛丽 波平斯
You look like Mary Poppins.
他酷炫吗
Is he cool?
当然 他酷的很
Hell yeah, he's cool.
我是玛丽 波平斯 呦吼
I'm Mary Poppins, y'all!
曼迪斯 小心
Mantis! Look out!
她昏迷了
She's just unconscious.
炸弹什么时候爆炸
How long 'til the bomb goes off?
如果格鲁特不会杀了我们的话
In the unlikely event that Groot doesn't kill us all...
大概六分钟
about 6 minutes.
克拉格林 我们需要救生舱逃离
Kraglin, we need the quadrant for an extraction.
- 倒计时五分钟 - 好的 船长
- T- minus 5 minutes. - Aye, cap'n.
克拉格林来的时候 得有人在上面接应
Somebody's gotta be on top when Kraglin arrives.
德拉克斯 带曼迪斯上去
Drax, take Mantis.
嗷 我的小胸胸
Ow! My nipples!
卡魔拉
Gamora!
彼得
Peter!
共渡难关
Get over it.
彼得我知道你不想这样的
Come now, Peter. I know this isn't what you want.
我这父亲得有多差 才能让你做出这样的选择
What kind of father would I be to let you make this choice?
很快 彼得 我们就会是世间万物
Soon, Peter, we will be all there is.
所以 别 再 招 惹 我
So stop pissing me off!
我们得上到撤离点那儿去
We have to get up to the extraction point.
跳
Go!
我告诉过你
I told you.
我不想一个人独享这一切
I don't want to do this alone.
你不能否认
You can not deny...
宇宙赋予你的目的
the purpose the universe has bestowed upon you.
所有人 后退 这里很危险
Everyone, I need you to stay back, it's not safe...
那是什么
What is that?
我们不需要这样的 彼得
It doesn't need to be like this, Peter.
你为什么要毁掉我们的好机会呢
Why are you destroying our chance?
别再伪装自己了
Stop pretending you aren't what you are.
你是亿里挑一
One in billions.
甚至更厉害
Trillions. Even more.
一个微小的生命又能有多大的贡献
What greater meaning can a life possibly have to offer?
我控制我的箭用的可不是脑子 孩子
I don't use my head to fly the arrows, boy!
我用的是心
I use my heart...
你不该杀了我妈妈 还毁了我的随身听
You shouldn't have killed my mom and squished my Walkman.
格鲁特 格鲁特 如果你能听到的话 快点
Groot! Groot, if you can hear me, hurry up!
我不知道奎尔能拖他多久
I'm not sure how long Quill can keep him distracted!
格鲁特 快
Groot! Hurry!
勇度 快要爆炸了
Yondu, we're about to blow!
- 去飞船上 - 不能抛下奎尔
- Get to the ship! - Not without Quill!
你得照顾小树苗
You need to take care of the twig!
也不能抛下你
Not without you.
我这一生都没做对过什么 小老鼠
I ain't done nothing right my whole damn life, rat.
你得给我这个机会
You need to give me this.
一套太空服 一个氧气罐
A spacesuit and an aero- rig.
我一样只有一个了
I only have one of each.
我
I...
我是格鲁特
I am Groot!
他说什么
What's that?
他说
He says,
欢迎加入奇葩的银河护卫队
"Welcome to the freaking Guardians of the Galaxy".
不过他没用奇葩这个词
Only he didn't use "freaking".
拜拜 小树苗
Bye, twig.
我们得好好讨论一下你说脏话的问题了
We're gonna have to have a real discussion about your language.
彼得人呢
Where's Peter?
火箭 他在哪儿
Rocket, where is he?
火箭
Rocket?
火箭 看着我 他在哪里
Rocket, look at me! Where is he?
不行 他不来我不走
No, I'm not leaving without him.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我只能承受失去一个朋友的痛苦
I can only afford to lose one friend today.
克拉格林 开船
Kraglin, go!
等等
Wait.
等一等再走
Let's hold back.
火箭 奎尔在哪儿
Rocket, where's Quill?
火箭 奎尔在哪里
火箭
Rocket!
奎尔在哪里
Where's Quill?
奎尔到底在哪儿
不 我们得让它停下 我们得让它停下
No, we need to stop it. We need to stop it.
住手 听着 听我说
Stop, listen! Listen to me.
你是个神
You are a god.
如果你杀了我
If you kill me...
你就会和别人一样平庸
you'll be just like everybody else.
那又怎么样
What's wrong with that?
不
No!
他可能是你的生父 孩子 但他不是你爸爸
He may have been your father, boy, but he wasn't your daddy.
抱歉我这一辈子没做对过什么事
I'm sorry I didn't do none of it right.
你他妈真是太幸运了
Damn lucky you my boy.
什么
What?
勇度 你要干什么 你不能这样
Yondu, what are you doing? You can't.
勇度
Yondu!
不
No.
No!
不
不不不
No! No!
不
Oh! No!
我给卡魔拉说过
I told Gamora
我小时候是怎么假装大卫 哈赛尔霍夫是我爸爸的
how when I was a kid, I used to pretend David Hasselhoff was my dad.
他是地球上的歌手和演员 非常有名
He is a singer and actor from Earth, really famous guy.
刚刚 我才意识到
Earlier, it struck me...
勇度虽然没有会说话的车
Yondu didn't have a talking car
但他有一支会飞的箭
but he did have a flying arrow.
他没有天籁般的声线
He didn't have the beautiful voice of an angel...
但他的口哨却是天籁
but he did have the whistle of one.
勇度和大卫 哈塞尔霍夫都爱冒险
Both Yondu and David Hasselhoff went on kick- ass adventures...
都爱勾搭性感姑娘
and hooked up with hot women...
都爱和机器人打架
and fought robots.
大卫 哈塞尔霍夫毕竟不是我爸爸
I guess David Hasselhoff did kind of end up being my dad after all.
我唯一的爸爸 是你 勇度
Only, it was you, Yondu.
我有个很酷炫的爸爸
I had a pretty cool dad.
我现在想说的是
What I'm trying to say here is...
有时候你穷尽一生想要得到的
sometimes the thing you're searching for your whole life...
可能一直都在你身边
it's right there by your side all along.
只是你没有意识到
You don't even know it.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
他确实叫你小树苗来着
He did call you twig.
星云
Nebula.
我那时候和你一样是个孩子
I was a child like you.
我每天都在想 我怎么才能见到明天的太阳
I was concerned with staying alive until the next day, every day.
我从来都没想过灭霸会怎么对待你
And I never considered what Thanos was doing to you.
我想弥补我的过错
I'm trying to make it right.
宇宙里有许多像你一样的小女孩身陷囹圄
There are little girls like you across the universe who are in danger.
你可以和我们一起帮助她们
You can stay with us and help them.
我去杀了灭霸也算是帮了他们
I will help them by killing Thanos.
我不知道你能不能杀了他
I don't know if that's possible.
你永远都是我的妹妹
You will always be my sister.
彼得
Pete!
船长在一个二手店给你找到了这个 他说你总有一天会回来的
The captain found this for you in a junker shop, said you'd come back to the fold someday.
- 这是什么 - 这叫MP3
- What is it? - It's called a Zune.
现在地球人都听这个
It's what everybody's listening to on Earth nowadays.
- 里面存了300首歌 - 300首
- It's got 300 songs on it. - 300 songs?
等等
Wait.
火箭用零件把它重新组装了
Rocket grabbed the pieces and re- assembled it.
我想勇度是想让你继承它的
But I think Yondu would want you to have it.
谢谢你
Thanks.
船长
Cap'n.
他们来了
They came.
那是什么
What is it?
我给勇度的掠夺者旧友们发了消息
I sent word to Yondu's old Ravager buddies.
告诉他们勇度的事迹
And told them what he did.
这是掠夺者的葬礼
It's a Ravager funeral.
他终究没有让我们失望 船长
He didn't let us down after all, Captain.
是的 他没有 孩子
No he did not, son.
他没有
He did not.
珍重 老朋友
Fare thee well, old friend.
勇度 乌东塔 愿能在星空中看到你
Yondu Udonta, I will see you in the stars.
- 他没有赶走他们 - 是的
- He didn't chase them away. - No.
尽管他冲他们大喊大叫
Even though he yelled at 'em.
尽管他总是很刻薄
And was always mean.
还偷了他不需要的电池
And he stole batteries he didn't need.
当然不会赶他走了
Well of course not.
怎么了
What?
只是
It's just...
某种不言而喻的事
some unspoken thing.
真漂亮
It's beautiful.
是啊
Yes.
你也很漂亮
And so are you.
内在美
On the inside.